## RIDWAN ABDULSALAM

#### FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

+234 812 439 6303

🔀 riliwanademola@yahoo.com

Lagos Nigeria

#### PROFILE

A Dedicated and efficient Fullstack Devloper with experience in frontend development and backend development to develop fully functioning web application and also creating a stellar finished product.

Frontend: I am responsible in building Responsive and User-friendly dynamic Frontend User interface and also Optimizing user experience . Backend: My goal as a backend developer is the ability to Oversea the overall architecture and infrastructure of a system, Design secured Servers/Database and also involve in API development and Administration.

I actively seek out new technologies and stay up-to-date on industry trends and advancements. This has allowed me to stay ahead of curve and deliver exceptional work to all my client.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS













NextJS Advanced







nede Nodejs Advanced



MongoDB Advanced



Intermediate



#### EDUCATION

## National Diploma -Computer Science

Yaba College of Technology Lagos Nigeria 2017

## Higher National Diploma -

#### Computer Science

Yaba College of Technology Lagos Nigeria 2019

#### PROJECT AND ACTIVITIES

#### Final year project-Online Car Rentals And Driver Hiring System

- Gathered project requirements and specifications.
- Learnt alot about Internet of Things.
- Designed and developed the parts user interface .

#### SOFT SKILLS

Problem Solving Great attention to detail Highly organized Willing to accept feedback Desire and willingness to learn Excellent communication skills Giving clear feedback Facilitating others

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# RAOATECH IT-ELECTROMECH LIMITED - Lagos Nigeria - Fullstack

AUG 2020 - ONGOING(Hybrid)

- Implement new features and working on numerous pages for various internal company projects.
- Building reusable components with storybook.
- Work with QA on developing testing processes, frameworks and automation strategies.
- Build intuitive,accessible,consistent,performant and well-tested products.
- Supervise and assist in training interns in the engineering team .
- Utilized Linear and Notion to track and prioritize tasks.
- Implemented designs that suits client requirements.
- Improved website performance and user experience.
- Collaborated with product team to implement new feature development.

#### SPOTTR - Lagos Nigeria - Frontend Developer

MAR 2022 - JUNE 2022 (Remote / Contract)

- Collaborate with product team and backend team to design, develop, test, improve web applications.
- Redesigned existing app and implemented new features.
- Develop web products by bringing wireframes and designs to live.
- Debug and improve code for website performance and user experience.
- Collaborated with product team to implement new feature development.
- Refactoring and Optimizing code for loading speed and performance.

### $OBIG\ TECHNOLOGIES\ -\ Lagos\ Nigeria\ -\ Fullstack (Intern)$

AUG 2019 - JULY 2020

- Learned how to convert design prototypes into website and web
  application using programming language such as Html, css, JavaScript
  and also used frameworks for frontend development such as Reactjs,
  Nextjs.
- Learned how to Implement REST and graphlal APIs.
- Database Implementation with SQL and no SQL./li>
- Learned to interact and communicate with the team and handle feedback about work.



- Implemented designs that suits client requirements.
- Improved website performance and user experience.
- Gained experience developing, testing and deploying web applications.
- Collaborated with product team to implement new feature development.

Github Profile: Sirlahm

in Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ridwan-abdulsalam-81bba01b1

Portfolio:ridwanabdulsalam.netlify.app